<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CodersNotebook</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_menu_screen_01">menu_screen_01</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash">Splash</string>
    <string name="title_activity_css">CSS</string>
    <string name="html_title">HTML hints</string>
    <string name="css_title">CSS hints</string>
    <string name="logo">picture</string>
    <string name="contact_me">Contact me</string>

    <string name="information"> Information </string>
    <string name="about_project_title01">About project</string>
    <string name="about_project_title02"> Author(s) </string>
    <string name="about_project_01"> Application is made as a part of college individual project. \n
    The main idea of this project is to put together as much information as possible to help beginner developers.
    Application does not require internet access, so information is always in your pocket.</string>
    <string name="about_project_02"> \n Maria Kazydub \n</string>

    <string name="explore">EXPLORE</string>

    <string name="logo1">html_logo_1</string>
    <string name="html_title_name1">Start to build</string>
    <string name="html_title_name1_content1">Basic code that will help beginner to build any HTML page from scratch and also open it in WEB browser.
    Explained how to save file correctly.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_content_01">html_content_01</string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_01">To start to build a website we do not need any fancy programms and extra software.
    Any computer will be able to do the job, regardless its specifications.\n
    So we begin ... </string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_02">Open Notepad (preinstalled on all Windows machines), icon on the left, or download Notepad ++,
    icon on the right. Believe it or not, that is basically  the software that is used for creating most of the programms.
    Then add code below and save file as index.html. Or give any other name, but keep .html extention.</string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_03"> <![CDATA[
    <html> \n
    <title> </title> \n
    <body> \n

    This is my first page \n
    </body> \n

   </html>
    ]]>  </string>
    <string name="notepad">notepad</string>


    <string name="logo2">html_logo_2</string>
    <string name="html_title_name2">Fonts</string>
    <string name="html_title_name2_content2">Explanation of font sizes \n
        Make your text smaller, bigger, just as you like it.\n
        Also provided some examples for changing font faces, so you will be able to make your page look more beautiful
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_01">
       In HTML font is separated into different groups. One group is for displaying headings and another to display content.
        But you can use any font as you like. \n
        Please note that all content goest into BODY part of a page. In the future only code from body part will be displayed.
        Here is a sample of header font. It has 6 sizes and it is bold by default.
    </string>

    <string name="html_02_tutor_02"><![CDATA[
    <body> \n

    <h1> Size 1 </h1> \n
    <h2> Size 2 </h2> \n
    <h3> Size 3 </h3> \n
    <h4> Size 4 </h4> \n
    <h5> Size 5 </h5> \n
    <h6> Size 6 </h6> \n
    </body> \n
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_03">To display content and align text on a page paragraphs are used.
    When paragraph tag is used browser will create additional space before and after text and next paragraph will aotomatically start
        on new line.
    \n
    Tags can contain another tags inside for example, if you want to make text bigger, change a color of a certain word
    or insert a hyperlink.</string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_04"><![CDATA[
        <p> <font size="1"> font size 1</font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="2"> font size 2</font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="6"> font size 6 </font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="3"> font size 3</font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="7"> font size 7 </font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="4"> font size 4 </font> </p> \n
        <p> <font size="5"> font size 5 </font> </p> \n

        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_05"> <![CDATA[
    <font face="Cracked" size="4"> Cracked font</font> <br> \n
    <font face="ArCSI"> ArCSI font </font> <br> \n
    <font face="Rockwell"> Rockwell font </font> <br> \n
    <font face="Comic sans MS"> Comic sans MS font </font> <br> \n
    <font face= "Verdana"> Verdana font </font> <br> \n
    <font face="Skia"> Skia font </font> <br> \n

    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_06"> Here br tag is used to break the line and start next element on the next line. \n
        In one of the next chapter you will see other tags for page layout.
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_07"> In other words, any font you see in Word or another text editor can be used
     on your page in font face.</string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_08"> You can highlight separate words by color or type (bold, italic, underlined).
    Please note that links are underlined by default. </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_09"> <![CDATA[
    <font face="Skia" size="6" color="#ff0000"> Skia font </font> <br> \n
    <font size="6" face="Rockwell" color="blue"> Rockwell font </font> <br>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_10"> <![CDATA[
    <b> bold text </b> <br> \n
    <font size="5"> <u> underlined text </u> </font> <br> \n
    <font size="3"> <i> italic text  </i> </font> <br>
    ]]></string>


    <string name="logo3">html_logo_3</string>
    <string name="html_title_name3">Tables</string>
    <string name="html_title_name3_content3"> Explanation of tables. \n
    How and where to use them, how to structure tables and make them invisible on a page. \n
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_01"> Tables are used to arrange different information on a page, such as text or picturs and
    make design nice and clean. \n
        Tables can be visible or invisible for a user. All that is done by setting table border parameters.\n
        Every table is made of table rows (tr) and table data(td). \n
        By default table borders are invisible, but by adding "border = 1", border will apper.
        Number can vary, depending how you want your table to look like. \n
        Here are some examples..
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_02"><![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr> \n
	    <td> John  </td> \n
		<td> Smith </td> \n
	</tr> \n

    </table> \n ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_03">
        <![CDATA[
        <table> \n
	       <tr> \n
            <td bgcolor="yellow"> John  </td> \n
            <td bgcolor="00FF00"> Smith </td> \n
        </tr> \n

        </table> \n

        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_04"> Here bgcolor is used to show how to change background color
        and also display two table columns </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_05">Other, more complicated, examples of arranging cells in tables </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_06"> <![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr>  \n
		<td colspan="2"> Avengers  </td> \n

	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Tony </td> \n
		<td> Stark </td> \n
	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Bruce </td> \n
		<td> Banner </td> \n
	</tr> \n

    </table> \n
    ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_07"> Colspan is used to merge columns into one.
        Rows can be merged together as well. Number of columns or rows to merge can be equal or less than number of
    columns above or below and than number of columns to the right or to the left.</string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_08"> <![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td colspan="2"> Avengers  </td> \n

	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Tony </td> \n
		<td> Stark </td> \n
		<td rowspan="2"> friends </td> \n
	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Bruce </td> \n
		<td> Banner </td> \n


	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td colspan="3">just a cell </td> \n
	</tr> \n

</table> \n
    ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_09"> This example shows how columns are merged if number is less than number of columns below.
        For "Avengers" cell span in set to "2", but for "just a cell" span is set to "3", so merges all three columns.
    </string>

    <string name="html_title_name4">All about images</string>
    <string name="html_title_name4_content"> Wa want to use images in our fancy website, so
    here is explained how to insert them, make images clickable and describe content. </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_01"> Any webpage would not look nice without images or gallery. \n
    In this chapter I am trying to cover all basic options of adding images and make them clickable, so
        image can be inserted to the page as a button.
        To make your job easier, store images in the same folder where your index.html (first page) file is stored.
        Then check the code below..
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_02"> <![CDATA[
    <h2> Image example </h2> \n
    <img src="image.jpg"> \n
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_03">In this example there are no additional attributes added to the image. \n
    Image is displayed in its original size, not clickable or does not display any other information.\n
    Example below shows how to add extra information to the image.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_04"> To change size of a picture we need to add style parameter and corresponding attributes
    like height and width. Please note that font has the same size, but looks bigger because picture now smaller.\n
    alt is used to add a description for a picture.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_05"> <![CDATA[
    <h2> Image example </h2> \n
    <img src= "image.jpg" \n alt="flower" \n
	style= "width: 100px; \n height: 80px;">\n
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_06"> What if our website have many pictures or picture gallery
    and storing all picture together with .html files will make it difficult to use later?
    There is a solution, of course, simply put folder name as a path to the picture followed by file name.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_07"> Here you can see that in the folder with index.html file is another folder called
    Pictures with the picture file there. So path for insertion picture in that case will be </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_08">
        <![CDATA[
        <img src="pictures/image.jpg">
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="html_title_name5"> Links </string>
    <string name="html_title_name5_content"> Website is not a website without links. Otherwise it is just a page.\n
    Explore to see how to add links and convert any pictures onto a button.</string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_01"> Links are used to provide access to another internet resourses like pages, pictures,
    files and other. Links are also used to create a navigation menu of the website. \n
    Text or picture can be a link. Here are examples. \n
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_02"> <![CDATA[
    <a> </a>
    ]]> tag is used to create a hyperlink.
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_03">  <![CDATA[
    <a href="http://www.websitename"> Click me </a>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_04"> <![CDATA[
    <p> Just text \n
    <a href="http://www.websitename"> Click me </a> \n
     and text again \n
    </p>
    ]]> </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_05"> Link can refer to the file (picture in our example) to open it in new window
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_06"> <![CDATA[
        <a href="pictures/image.jpg"> click to see picture </a>
    ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_07"> Link will look like text, similar to the previous example, but text ill be different.\n
        But after clicking on that link picture from your local directory will be opened. >>>
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_08"> <![CDATA[
    <a href="http://www.websitename"> \n
    <img src="pictures/image.jpg"> \n
    </a>
    ]]> </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_09"> Picture can be modified and resized by adding parameters for size </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_10"> So now picture is clickable and will open any website or page it is refferenced to. 
    To link picture to another page on the same website use code below
    </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_11"> <![CDATA[
    <a href="index.html"> \n
    <img src="pictures/image.jpg"> \n
    </a>
    ]]> </string>
    <string name="html_05_tutor_12"> In this example simply add page you want user to go within the same website into
    <![CDATA[ <a>]]> tag after href=
    </string>

    <string name="html_title_name6"> Other useful tags </string>
    <string name="html_title_name6_content"> Here I tried to put together other tags that will help to make page look better
        using separators, lines and other things like special characters. </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_01"> Most pages use other elements there to separate content, add lines etc. \n
    Here is a list of these elements to help to make page look better. These tags can be inserted into text, around words,
        after paragraphs. Just anywhere where you feel like adding it.</string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_02"> <![CDATA[ <br>  ]]> tag is used to insert a horizontal break between two elements.
    If you want ot have a bigger break simply put few <![CDATA[ <br> ]]> one after another. \n
    For example
    <![CDATA[  <br> <br> <br>]]> \n
    or \n
    <![CDATA[ <br> \n <br> \n <br>]]></string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_03"> one break here </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_04"> three breaks here </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_05"> Lines can also be used as seperators of content.\n
    Horizontal line is added with <![CDATA[ <hr> ]]> tag. \n
        By adding tag between two elemnts, next element will apper on the next line after the horizontal line. \n
        By default line takes whole page length.
    </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_06">

        word 1 <![CDATA[ <hr> ]]> word 2
    </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_07"> Next question you will have is how to add vertical line. \n
    There is no tag for doing that, but we can always modify our parameters for horizontal line to make it vertical.\n
    To do that we add extra styling parameters to our tag ... </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_08">
        <![CDATA[
              <hr style="width:0.5px; height:50px; position: absolute; left: 35px;"/>
        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_09">
    Here we added some parameters for line width and height. \n
    We alo positioned our line absolutely relatively to the left edge of the screen. \n
    Try to change it to right and see what will happen.</string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_name">Special symbols</string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_10"> Sometimes we need to add some extra space between the words
        or special symbol. By defaul html will show only one space regardless how many are there in the code.
    But there is a way to add more by using \n
    <![CDATA[&nbsp]]>. \n
        If you want to see 10 spaces, add  <![CDATA[&nbsp]]> 10 times( actually 9, as one space will be shown if exists in the code).\n
        Other symbols:
    </string>
    <string name="html_06_tutor_11">\n
    <![CDATA[ &lt]]> ; - less than \n
    <![CDATA[ &gt]]> ; - greater than \n
    <![CDATA[ &amp]]> ; - ampersand \n
    <![CDATA[ &cent]]> ; - cent \n
    <![CDATA[ &pound]]> ; - pound \n
    <![CDATA[ &yen]]> ; - yen \n
    <![CDATA[ &euro]]> ; - euro \n
    <![CDATA[ &copy]]> ; - copyright \n
    <![CDATA[ &reg]]> ; - registered trademark \n
    <![CDATA[ &trade]]> ; - trademark \n
    <![CDATA[ &larr]]> ; - arrow left  \n
    <![CDATA[ &rarr]]> ; - arrow right  \n
    <![CDATA[ &uarr]]> ; - arrow up \n
    <![CDATA[ &darr]]> ; - arrow down \n
    <![CDATA[ &spades]]> ; - black spades \n
    <![CDATA[ &clubs]]> ; - black clubs \n
    <![CDATA[ &hearts]]> ; - black hearts \n
    <![CDATA[ &diams]]> ; - black diamonds \n

    </string>


    <string name="title_activity_html_01">html_01</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_02">html_02</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_03">html_03</string>

    <string name="css_title_name1"> Link your Style </string>
    <string name="css_title_name1_content"> Here is shown how to link .css file to the html file to styles will be applied. \n
    Styling can be done for the whole website or for different pages separately.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_04">html_04</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_05">html_05</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_06">html_06</string>
    <string name="title_activity_more_info">more_info</string>

</resources>
