<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CodersNotebook</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_menu_screen_01">menu_screen_01</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash">Splash</string>
    <string name="title_activity_css">CSS</string>
    <string name="html_title">HTML hints</string>
    <string name="css_title">CSS hints</string>
    <string name="logo">picture</string>

    <string name="explore">EXPLORE</string>

    <string name="logo1">html_logo_1</string>
    <string name="html_title_name1">Start to build</string>
    <string name="html_title_name1_content1">Basic code that will help beginner to build any HTML page from scratch and also open it in WEB browser.
    Explained how to save file correctly.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_content_01">html_content_01</string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_01">To start to build a website we do not need any fancy programms and extra software.
    Any computer will be able to do the job, regardless its specifications.\n
    So we begin ... </string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_02">Open Notepad (preinstalled on all Windows machines), icon on the left, or download Notepad ++,
    icon on the right. Believe it or not, that is basically  the software that is used for creating most of the programms.
    Then add code below and save file as index.html. Or give any other name, but keep .html extention.</string>
    <string name="html_01_tutor_03"> <![CDATA[
    <html> \n
    <title> </title> \n
    <body> \n

    This is my first page \n
    </body> \n

   </html>
    ]]>  </string>
    <string name="notepad">notepad</string>


    <string name="logo2">html_logo_2</string>
    <string name="html_title_name2">Font size</string>
    <string name="html_title_name2_content2">Explanation of font sizes \n
        Make your text smaller, bigger, just as you like it.\n
        Also provided some examples fo changing font faces, so you will be able to make your page look more beautiful
    </string>
    <string name="html_02_tutor_01">
        In HTML font size is available in 6 different variations. To hange the size of the text simply wrap text into
        corresponding tags. All tags are listed below ... \n
        Please note that all content goest into BODY part of a page. In the future only code from body part will be displayed.
    </string>

    <string name="html_02_tutor_02"><![CDATA[
    <body> \n

    <h1> Size 1 </h1> \n
    <h2> Size 2 </h2> \n
    <h3> Size 3 </h3> \n
    <h4> Size 4 </h4> \n
    <h5> Size 5 </h5> \n
    <h6> Size 6 </h6> \n
    </body> \n
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="logo3">html_logo_3</string>
    <string name="html_title_name3">Tables</string>
    <string name="html_title_name3_content3"> Explanation of tables. \n
    How and where to use them, how to structure tables and make them invisible on a page. \n
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_01"> Tables are used to arrange different information on a page, such as text or picturs and
    make design nice and clean. \n
        Tables can be visible or invisible for a user. All that is done by setting table border parameters.\n
        Every table is made of table rows (tr) and table data(td). \n
        By default table borders are invisible, but by adding "border = 1", border will apper.
        Number can vary, depending how you want your table to look like. \n
        Here are some examples..
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_02"><![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr> \n
	    <td> John  </td> \n
		<td> Smith </td> \n
	</tr> \n

    </table> \n ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_03">
        <![CDATA[
        <table> \n
	       <tr> \n
            <td bgcolor="yellow"> John  </td> \n
            <td bgcolor="00FF00"> Smith </td> \n
        </tr> \n

        </table> \n

        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_04"> Here bgcolor is used to show how to change background color
        and also display two table columns </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_05">Other, more complicated, examples of arranging cells in tables </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_06"> <![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr>  \n
		<td colspan="2"> Avengers  </td> \n

	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Tony </td> \n
		<td> Stark </td> \n
	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Bruce </td> \n
		<td> Banner </td> \n
	</tr> \n

    </table> \n
    ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_07"> Colspan is used to merge columns into one.
        Rows can be merged together as well. Number of columns or rows to merge can be equal or less than number of
    columns above or below and than number of columns to the right or to the left.</string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_08"> <![CDATA[
    <table border="1"> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td colspan="2"> Avengers  </td> \n

	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Tony </td> \n
		<td> Stark </td> \n
		<td rowspan="2"> friends </td> \n
	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td> Bruce </td> \n
		<td> Banner </td> \n


	</tr> \n
	<tr> \n
		<td colspan="3">just a cell </td> \n
	</tr> \n

</table> \n
    ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="html_03_tutor_09"> This example shows how columns are merged if number is less than number of columns below.
        For "Avengers" cell span in set to "2", but for "just a cell" span is set to "3", so merges all three columns.
    </string>

    <string name="html_title_name4">All about images</string>
    <string name="html_title_name4_content"> Wa want to use images in our fancy website, so
    here is explained how to insert them, make images clickable and describe content. </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_01"> Any webpage would not look nice without images or gallery. \n
    In this chapter I am trying to cover all basic options of adding images and make them clickable, so
        image can be inserted to the page as a button.
        To make your job easier, store images in the same folder where your index.html (first page) file is stored.
        Then check the code below..
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_02"> <![CDATA[
    <h2> Image example </h2> \n
    <img src="image.jpg"> \n
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_03">In this example there are no additional attributes added to the image. \n
    Image is displayed in its original size, not clickable or does not display any other information.\n
    Example below shows how to add extra information to the image.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_04"> To change size of a picture we need to add style parameter and corresponding attributes
    like height and width. Please note that font has the same size, but looks bigger because picture now smaller.\n
    alt is used to add a description for a picture.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_05"> <![CDATA[
    <h2> Image example </h2> \n
    <img src= "image.jpg" \n alt="flower" \n
	style= "width: 100px; \n height: 80px;">\n
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_06"> What if our website have many pictures or picture gallery
    and storing all picture together with .html files will make it difficult to use later?
    There is a solution, of course, simply put folder name as a path to the picture followed by file name.</string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_07"> Here you can see that in the folder with index.html file is another folder called
    Pictures with the picture file there. So path for insertion picture in that case will be </string>
    <string name="html_04_tutor_08">
        <![CDATA[
        <img src="pictures/image.jpg">
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_html_01">html_01</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_02">html_02</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_03">html_03</string>

    <string name="css_title_name1"> Link your Style </string>
    <string name="css_title_name1_content"> Here is shown how to link .css file to the html file to styles will be applied. \n
    Styling can be done for the whole website or for different pages separately.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_html_04">html_04</string>

</resources>
